ROBERTO FLORES

Senior Software Engineer

@ robertofloresdev0119@gmail.com

@ linkedin.com/in/robertoflores097

Prussel, Belgium

SUMMARY

Professional software engineer with 10+ years of comprehensive experience in the Software Development industry. Provides strong technical direction across multiple projects. Experienced with the full software development lifecycle from planning to launch. Responsible and articulate individual with strengths in solutions optimization, mobile and cloud solutions, and global project management. A self-motivated, avid learner.

EXPERIENCE

01/2022 - 02/2024 •

Senior Software Engineer

London, UK

Cyberr

- · Mentored and provided technical guidance to an engineering team of over 5 members.
- Led and participated in the development of various web and mobile applications using cutting-edge technologies, including React, React Native, Next.js, Node.js, Express, and NestIS.
- · Played a key role in database design using **MongoDB**, **PostgreSQL**, **Elasticsearch**, and **MySQL**.
- · Actively contributed to code reviews, ensuring code quality, maintainability, and adherence to best practices.
- · Responsible for the DevOps role utilizing **GCP**, **AWS**, **Kubernetes**, and **Docker**.
- · Experienced in creating microservices using AWS Lambda, DynamoDB, and S3.

06/2019 - 12/2021

Software Engineer

Denver, CO, USA

Velocity Global

- · Led the upgrade of old software to new technologies, transitioning from **AngularJS** to **React** and **Python Django** to **Next.js**, which improved performance.
- Developed and maintained client web and mobile apps using **AngularJS**, **React.js**, **React Native**, **Next.js**, **Node.js**, **Python Django**, and **Ruby on Rails**.
- · Involved in designing databases with **MySQL**, **PostgreSQL**, **Redis**, and **MongoDB**, focusing on efficiency and data integrity.
- · Conducted code reviews to ensure high-quality, maintainable code and compliance with best coding practices.
- · Implemented and managed **automated testing** and **continuous integration processes** to improve code quality and deployment efficiency.
- · Supported the CTO with various management tasks as high-level architectural decisions.

06/2017 - 06/2019

Full Stack Developer

Brussel, Belgium

3E

- · Created RESTful API endpoints using **Node.js**, **Django**, **Flask**, **Laravel**, **MongoDB**, **MySQL**, **PostgreSQL**, **Redis**, **Amazon Web Services**, **Azure** and **GCP**.
- · Created automated testing framework in **Mocha** + **Chai** + **Simon** for unit tests and e2e UI tests
- Developed e-commerce websites and mobile applications, encompassing design, coding, testing, and maintenance whilst supervising a team of 3 intern developers.
- Spearheaded the successful refactoring of the client-side web architecture to introduce a reliable SPA.
- Optimized web applications for maximum speed and scalability, resulting in a 30% reduction in page load times and a 20% increase in overall system performance.
- · Collaborated with the DevOps team to implement continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD) practices, reducing software release times and minimizing production issues.

EXPERIENCE

07/2014 - 05/2017 •

Front End Developer

Brussel, Belgium

Adiutum

- Participated in development and maintain of ecommerce websites using Python, PHP, Laravel, Node.js, MySQL, jQuery and React.
- Developed 100+ unit tests to verify the functionality of user interfaces, back-end processing, connectivity, and relational database interactions using MySQL.
- · Worked on fun mobile application which turns any iOS device into musical instrument.
- · Developed clear specifications for project plans using customer requirements.
- · Implemented fully responsive pixel-perfect cross-platform designs in React and SASS.
- · Cooperated with the UX department to create a new look and feel for the website, implemented changes

EDUCATION

2010 - 2014

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science
UCLouvain Saint-Louis Bruxelles

SKILLS

Full Stack Development	Mobile App Development	Test Driven Development	Agile Development
DevOps			

CERTIFICATION

Full-Stack Web Development with React Certification

Front End Web Development Certification

Back End Web Development Certification

Free Code Camp Full Stack Development Certification

Mobile App Development Certification